export default {
  id: 'mid_2b',
  name: '상용한자(중학2/한자찾기)',
  data: [
    { question: '독:동네/음:ぼう、[ぼっ]', answer: ['坊'] },
    { question: '독:さまた(げる)/음:ぼう', answer: ['妨'] },
    { question: '독:つむ(ぐ)/음:ぼう', answer: ['紡'] },
    { question: '독:기름/음:ぼう', answer: ['肪'] },
    { question: '독:ふさ/음:ぼう', answer: ['房'] },
    { question: '독:かんば(しい)/음:ほう', answer: ['芳'] },
    { question: '독:なら(う)/음:ほう', answer: ['倣'] },
    { question: '독:おご(る)/음:ごう', answer: ['傲'] },
    { question: '독:い(む)、い(まわしい)/음:き', answer: ['忌'] },
    { question: '독:왕비/음:ひ', answer: ['妃'] },
    { question: '독:잡을/음:は', answer: ['把'] },
    { question: '독:あま(い)、あま(える)、あま(やかす)/음:かん', answer: ['甘'] },
    { question: '독:감색/음:こん', answer: ['紺'] },
    { question: '독:はなは(だしい)/음:じん', answer: ['甚'] },
    { question: '독:た(える)/음:かん', answer: ['耐'] },
    { question: '독:헤아릴/음:かん', answer: ['勘'] },
    { question: '독:아무/음:ぼう', answer: ['某'] },
    { question: '독:はか(る)/음:ぼう、[む]', answer: ['謀'] },
    { question: '독:중매할/음:ばい', answer: ['媒'] },
    { question: '독:바둑, 장기/음:き', answer: ['棋'] },
    { question: '독:바둑, 바둑돌/음:ご', answer: ['碁'] },
    { question: '독:あざむ(く)/음:ぎ', answer: ['欺'] },
    { question: '독:길할/음:きち、きつ', answer: ['吉'] },
    { question: '독:つ(める)、つ(まる)、つ(む)/음:きつ', answer: ['詰'] },
    { question: '독:천연두/음:とう', answer: ['痘'] },
    { question: '독:たたか(う)/음:とう', answer: ['闘'] },
    { question: '독:한/음:いち', answer: ['壱'] },
    { question: '독:두/음:に', answer: ['弐'] },
    { question: '독:は(く)/음:と', answer: ['吐'] },
    { question: '독:꺾을/음:ざ', answer: ['挫'] },
    { question: '독:むつ(まじい)、むつ(む)/음:ぼく', answer: ['睦'] },
    { question: '독:みささぎ/음:りょう', answer: ['陵'] },
    { question: '독:がけ/음:がい', answer: ['崖'] },
    { question: '독:물가/음:がい', answer: ['涯'] },
    { question: '독:아름다울/음:か', answer: ['佳'] },
    { question: '독:か(ける)、か(かる)、か(かり)/음:', answer: ['掛'] },
    { question: '독:봉할/음:ふう、ほう', answer: ['封'] },
    { question: '독:あかつき/음:ぎょう', answer: ['暁'] },
    { question: '독:희생/음:せい', answer: ['牲'] },
    { question: '독:성씨/음:せい、しょう', answer: ['姓'] },
    { question: '독:높을/음:りゅう', answer: ['隆'] },
    { question: '독:임신할/음:にん', answer: ['妊'] },
    { question: '독:드릴/음:てい', answer: ['呈'] },
    { question: '독:みだ(ら)/음:いん', answer: ['淫'] },
    { question: '독:조정/음:てい', answer: ['廷'] },
    { question: '독:배/음:てい', answer: ['艇'] },
    { question: '독:왕성할/음:おう', answer: ['旺'] },
    { question: '독:くる(う)、くる(おしい)/음:きょう', answer: ['狂'] },
    { question: '독:마개/음:せん', answer: ['栓'] },
    { question: '독:설명할/음:せん', answer: ['詮'] },
    { question: '독:빚/음:さい', answer: ['債'] },
    { question: '독:つ(ける)、つ(かる)/음:', answer: ['漬'] },
    { question: '독:こ(う)、う(ける)/음:せい、[しん]', answer: ['請'] },
    { question: '독:새길/음:めい', answer: ['銘'] },
    { question: '독:かま/음:ふ', answer: ['釜'] },
    { question: '독:から(む)、から(まる)、から(める)/음:らく', answer: ['絡'] },
    { question: '독:さと(る)/음:ご', answer: ['悟'] },
    { question: '독:か(れ)る、か(らす)/음:こ', answer: ['枯'] },
    { question: '독:금고/음:こ', answer: ['錮'] },
    { question: '독:낱/음:か', answer: ['箇'] },
    { question: '독:허락할/음:だく', answer: ['諾'] },
    { question: '독:숨길/음:とく', answer: ['匿'] },
    { question: '독:가혹할/음:か', answer: ['苛'] },
    { question: '독:기이할/음:き', answer: ['奇'] },
    { question: '독:[さい]/음:', answer: ['埼'] },
    { question: '독:험할/음:さき', answer: ['崎'] },
    { question: '독:말탈/음:き', answer: ['騎'] },
    { question: '독:의자/음:い', answer: ['椅'] },
    { question: '독:うかがう/음:し', answer: ['伺'] },
    { question: '독:이을/음:し', answer: ['嗣'] },
    { question: '독:ねたむ/음:と', answer: ['妬'] },
    { question: '독:개척할, 박을/음:たく', answer: ['拓'] },
    { question: '독:관리/음:り', answer: ['吏'] },
    { question: '독:おき/음:ちゅう', answer: ['沖'] },
    { question: '독:くし/음:', answer: ['串'] },
    { question: '독:わずら(う)/음:かん', answer: ['患'] },
    { question: '독:법칙/음:ろ', answer: ['呂'] },
    { question: '독:짝/음:りょ', answer: ['侶'] },
    { question: '독:다락/음:ろう', answer: ['楼'] },
    { question: '독:こと/음:きん', answer: ['琴'] },
    { question: '독:읊을/음:きん', answer: ['吟'] },
    { question: '독:ふく(む)、ふく(める)/음:がん', answer: ['含'] },
    { question: '독:비틀(짜낼)/음:ねん', answer: ['捻'] },
    { question: '독:むさぼ(る)/음:どん', answer: ['貪'] },
    { question: '독:검소할/음:けん', answer: ['倹'] },
    { question: '독:つるぎ/음:けん', answer: ['剣'] },
    { question: '독:탑/음:とう', answer: ['塔'] },
    { question: '독:탈/음:とう', answer: ['搭'] },
    { question: '독:맑을/음:しょう', answer: ['晶'] },
    { question: '독:잔치/음:えん', answer: ['宴'] },
    { question: '독:어두울/음:めい、みょう', answer: ['冥'] },
    { question: '독:막막할/음:ばく', answer: ['漠'] },
    { question: '독:막/음:まく', answer: ['膜'] },
    { question: '독:つの(る)/음:ぼ', answer: ['募'] },
    { question: '독:した(う)/음:ぼ', answer: ['慕'] },
    { question: '독:아침/음:たん、だん', answer: ['旦'] },
    { question: '독:ただ(し)/음:', answer: ['但'] },
    { question: '독:쓸개/음:たん', answer: ['胆'] },
    { question: '독:제단/음:だん、[たん]', answer: ['壇'] }
  ]
}
